Jinhyuk Yoon

jinhyukyoon@postech.ac.kr https://www.jinhyukyoon.com

I solve engineering, education, and art problem with my engineering background and ability of other colleagues. I love interacting with people and getting inspired through various projects such as research, design, art work, and education. Through technological and humanistic point of view, I've been trying to create inspirational experience.

Professional Experience

Samsung Electronics, Digital Appliances Division, Core Component R&D Lab

Jan 2019 - Present

Mechanical Design Intern

Analyze two-spring damper hinge and deploy the result on interaction data platform to simplify design process. Also propose possible mechanical improvements of mass produced hinge through computational analysis.

Sovoro Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

Communications Manager

Conducted UI/UX design of the service, catalog design, market research, and business activity related with public institution, educational institution, and people with hearing loss.

Korea Foundation for the Advancement of Science & Creativity

May 2016 - Jan 2018

Science Communicator

Gave talk, performed scientific street performance, and acted scientific play targeting adults as a finalist of FameLab Korea and science communicator commissioned by minister of Ministry of Science & ICT.

Asan Medical Center, Biomedical Engineering Research Center

Aug 2017 - Oct 2017

Research Intern

Designed concept prototype of Ankle Rehabilitation Assistant, inspired by Anklebot.

Leadership Experience

POSTECH, Student Election Committee

Sep 2016 - Nov 2016

Chairman

Organized the student election committee and run the election for central student president.

POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Student President

Directed student membership training, professor appreciation banquet, association program with KAIST and founded basketball and badminton club.

TEDxPOSTECH Nov 2014 – Nov 2015

Director

Organized TEDx event under the theme 'question' with 6 speakers. Regular application was fully booked in 50 seconds after opening. Conducted team building, speaker and sponsor contact, stage planning and host at the event.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

2014 - Present

Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

Have minor in Industrial management engineering. Expect to graduate with *Magna Cum Laude*

Awards and Honors

Commission Letter Minister of Ministry of Science & ICT commissioned me as a science communicator	2016
Finalist Nationwide Top 11 of the 3 rd FameLab Korea	2016
Runners up Artience Creation Challenge 30x30, 30 hours Hackathon project, hosted by British Council	2017
Honorable Mention 3 Minute Science Speech Contest hosted by POSTECH	2015
Student of the Year POSTECH, Department of Mechanical Engineering	2015, 2016
The 4th Prize The 2 nd POSTECH Hackathon	2016
National Academic Excellence Scholarship Korea Student Aid Foundation	2016 – Present
KT&G Foundation Scholarship POSTECH	2016
Jigok Scholarship	2014 - 2016

Skills and Tools

POSTECH

Programming Language

C, C++, JAVA, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MATLAB

Graphic DesignAdobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

3D Design & Analysis

Solidworks, NX

Selected Talks

Keynote Speech, "About Experience", POSTECH Alumni Conference for Freshman, Pohang	2018
Keynote Speech, "Engineering and Science Communication", The 5th Integrated Science Leading Teacher Training, Yeongcheon	2016
Keynote Speech, "About Science Communication", National Youth Science Exploration Competition, Gyeongju	2016
Talk, "Regain the lost life", Suseong-gu Gosan Library, Daegu	2018
Talk, "Regain the lost life", KIST Science Station , Seoul	2017
Talk, "Space food", The 13th Bohyeonsan Starlight Festival, Yeongcheon	2016
Talk, "Science, Engineering and Me", Seongji Highschool, Yongin	2017
Talk, "Communicate with Science", Mulgeum High School, Yangsan	2017
Talk, "Talk with Odd Engineering Student", Samsung Girl's High School, Busan	2017